I am the bone of my sword.
Steel is my body,
and fire is my blood.
I have created over
a thousand blades.
Unknown to Death,
nor known to Life.
Have withstood pain to
create many weapons.
Yet, those hands will
never hold anything.
So as I pray,
Unlimited Blade Works.
So that's how he
became a Heroic Spirit.
What an idiot.
In the face of absolute despair
That nearly burned
our hearts away
You still found the
courage to smile
Like you accepted it all
I lost my voice
And the things I wanted to say
But every time I
fell to my knees
I stood up and kept walking
We were looking for
the ideal white future
Our one and only hope
Now I may be left with nothing
But these raging
emotions that have
Nowhere to go
Still, I'll look for a new dawn
With more than one right answer
I won't stop
Until I find it
How long do you intend
to keep playing around?
The Fifth Contractor
Huh? Just until 7:30.
Any longer, and I'll
be late for school.
I wasn't referring to
your leaving for school.
I was referring to
the Holy Grail War.
Cooperating with another
Master isn't a bad idea.
But you've chosen the worst
possible partner you could.
Didn't I say I wouldn't break
my pact with Emiya-kun?
I admit he isn't
much use in a fight,
but I have no complaints
with him as an ally.
I mean...
I feel like Emiya-kun would
never betray me, no matter what.
Listen.
That boy isn't a winner.
If you must ally with someone,
even Caster would be better.
Don't be absurd, Archer.
Are you telling me to take a
common stance with that monster?
Yes, she is a monster, but
she behaves like a real mage.
And if you too are a mage, you
should prioritize results over ideals.
Your snide remarks won't work. I
don't intend to change my position.
What in the world
has gotten into you?
You've been acting strangely ever
since you got to know Emiya Shirou.
What happened to your
detached rationality?
Yes, I know I'm not myself.
But that's all because of the
nonsense you've been showing me.
What?
It's nothing. Forget it.
Anyway, since you're
my Servant, bear in
mind that I'll only do
what I think is right.
I'm not as naïve
as Emiya Shirou,
but there are some
things I won't budge on.
I won't compromise on
those—not for anyone.
What do you say to that, Archer?
What can I say?
It's a vassal's duty to support
his lord when she's out of sorts.
I'll watch over you from the
shadows until you're yourself again.
What's wrong with me?
I've been waking
up exhausted lately.
Well, those really
were beautiful swords.
Yeah, that's right.
I like them. Is that so bad?
That's all I had to tell you.
Also, I'm sure I don't
need to remind you
of this, but don't
forget to lock the doors.
Of course. That
goes without saying.
Hey, Issei.
What is it, Emiya?
I've been curious
about this for a while.
Are you and Kuzuki close?
Oh, I guess I never
told you, did I?
It's only natural that
we'd be on good terms.
After all, he's like a
surrogate big brother to me.
A big brother?
Souichirou—no,
Kuzuki-sensei has been staying at
the temple for the past three years or so.
He's the quiet type, but he's
a forthright and sincere man.
My respect for him is based on
our living under the same roof.
It's only natural that I should
look up to him as a brother.
Kuzuki lives at Ryuudou Temple?
Wha...
Tohsaka?
Student Council President, while we're on
the topic of this "big brother" of yours...
Has anything happened
at the temple recently?
I have nothing to say to someone
who'd stoop to eavesdropping!
Issei, I'd like to know as well.
Wh-What's going on with you two?
Especially after
the other day...
Well, I suppose one
thing comes to mind.
Kuzuki-sensei is
getting married soon.
About two weeks ago, he brought home a
woman whom he introduced as his fiancée.
Although it does strike me as
a bit odd, I'm happy for them.
We've given her special
permission to stay there.
They're living together in quarters
separate from the main temple for now.
We've found him.
After what happened with Issei,
I think it's crazy to suspect someone
just because they live at Ryuudou Temple.
Why?
He couldn't be more suspicious.
He must be the Master.
That "fiancée" of his is Caster.
There's no doubt.
We attack tonight.
Emiya-kun, you
should go prepare too.
Hang on.
Tonight?
Of course.
There's no guarantee that Kuzuki-sensei
will come to school tomorrow.
We'll test him on his way
home to see if he's a Master.
Test him? How?
I'll hit him with a
light Gandr shot.
Even if Kuzuki-sensei's a normal person,
he'll only end up bedridden for a few days.
That doesn't work either.
If he is a Master, it'll turn
into a fight then and there.
And then it'll be
too late to talk it out.
But that'd be all
the better for us.
What's the problem?
Well, if that happens,
you'll be in danger.
Oh, I don't really mind.
I'll just handle him myself.
Jeez.
Fine. I'll go with you.
Then you intend to attack
Caster's Master tonight?
Yeah. We still don't know for certain
that Kuzuki-sensei's the Master,
but at this point, we'll
just have to test him.
That's true.
I understand your
reluctance, Shirou.
But for now, let us go
along with Rin's plan.
I wish I could fight
more like he does.
What am I thinking?
When I called Fuji-nee—no,
Fujimura-sensei just now to check,
she said Kuzuki
hadn't left school yet.
Which means that he's still
following his usual routine tonight.
In which case, he'll be
leaving school any time now.
Rin, why is Archer not here?
I left him at home.
I don't want him around Caster.
What does that mean?
Let's hurry.
It's a straight road from
here to Ryuudou Temple,
so Kuzuki will
definitely pass this spot.
We'll set our trap
here and ambush him.
It's an ideal location,
don't you think?
It's nothing fancy, but I
can set up a magic field here
to completely soundproof the
area, though we'll still be visible.
A missile could blow this place sky
high and no one would hear a thing.
Well?
Excellent work.
Okay, Saber, as
for the plan itself...
Tohsaka!
Looks like he's here.
Hey, Tohsaka. I'm
thinking it really isn't Kuzuki.
Well, we'll know
once we do this.
Here goes.
Wait.
I thought I warned
you, Souichirou.
This was bound to happen, so you
should have remained at Ryuudou Temple.
I wouldn't say that.
After all, we have
caught our prey.
Now, come on out,
foolish little mage.
I shall give you three seconds.
After that, I shall respond
in kind to your aggression.
Emiya-kun, are you ready?
When I give the
signal, we start.
Sorry.
Save that for later, Tohsaka.
Huh?
Shirou!
Well, this is a surprise.
I see you've grown a little
smarter since I last saw you, boy.
Tohsaka and Emiya?
So it isn't only Matou. You
two are Masters as well.
You may be mages,
but it is still unfortunate.
Kuzuki, are you being
controlled by Caster?
You're such an irritating boy...
Perhaps I shall kill you.
Wait.
What makes you ask
that question, Emiya?
There must be a reason
why you'd suspect so.
Tell me.
You're a decent
human being, right?
You couldn't possibly be turning
a blind eye to what Caster's doing.
What Caster is doing?
Yeah.
Caster's taking mana
from people all across town.
To her, humans are
no more than sacrifices.
As long as Caster
keeps draining people,
it's only a matter of time
before she kills someone.
Before long, she'll have done
something that can't be fixed.
I understand.
You think that I, her Master,
was permitting her actions
because I was under her control.
Yeah. So if that's the case,
we'll only defeat Caster.
But if you gave Caster free
rein, knowing what she was up to,
that makes you no
more than a killer.
And I won't show
you mercy, either.
No, this is the first
I've heard of this.
However, Emiya...
Are Caster's actions
really so terrible?
What... did you say?
The deaths of strangers, no matter
the number, are of no concern to me.
Just as they are not the least
bit concerned about my life.
Kuzuki...
You're a mage, but
you'd involve outsiders?
I am no mage.
I'm simply a killer who's a
mere shadow of his former self.
I will not participate
in the Holy Grail War.
Whether Caster kills
people or you all fight
to the death, I will
do nothing but watch.
I will bear no responsibility
for your fighting,
and neither should any of you
bear responsibility for my life.
Do as you wish, Caster.
Whether you let them
live or kill them is up to you.
I see.
Then you have no
qualms about dying here,
Master of Caster?
Saber!
Not so fast, Saber.
Magic resistance?
Souichirou-sama!
You underestimate me, Saber!
His fists have been
fortified with magic?
You evade well.
Ah. So it is not your
eyes that are keen
but your intuition.
That's not possible.
It's fine to assume that a Master's
role is to provide rear support.
But there is an
exception to every rule.
There are also Masters, like me,
that can only fight on the front line.
Master...
What is it, Caster?
I shall handle Saber.
You see to the other Masters.
Very well.
Suits me.
You caught Saber by surprise,
but we just need to take
you out before you get close.
Tohsaka!
If I go down,
Tohsaka's dead.
I can't let that happen.
Weapons...
I need weapons
that will let me fight.
Powerful weapons.
Like the ones he had.
Trace on!
No way.
Those are...
Master!
Saber...
Wait.
That's enough.
Withdraw, Caster.
As you wish.
Shirou, are you injured?
Saber...
We blew it.
Now, Kuzuki won't set foot
outside of Ryuudou Temple.
You mean to give up
on slaying Caster, then?
You must be joking.
We can't let her run loose.
Of course we can't.
Anyway, Emiya-kun,
what were those?
I thought that fortification magic
was the only type you could do.
Well, it is. But projection was
the first type I succeeded at.
It ticks me off that you only
thought to mention this now.
So you're saying this
wasn't your first time?
I guess not.
But I could only mimic
the appearances of things.
Inside, they were always hollow.
That's why I'm as surprised
as you with what happened.
You picked up projection
before fortification?
Look, that was all I could do.
Kiritsugu said it was
totally useless in that
state and that I should
focus on fortification.
I suppose so.
I probably would
have said the same.
Still, it's awfully strange.
Tohsaka?
Let's go home.
Shirou!
I'm fine.
Oh, so this is where you were?
Don't worry. I'm
not here to complain.
I don't care where
you go or what you do.
But listen to this.
I have great news!
Kotomine says he'll turn a
blind eye to anything we do.
He seems to think
rather highly of you.
Well, he's a good
judge of people.
I'm thinking of giving him something as
a token of thanks once we get the Grail.
So we should start
killing everyone in sight.
Eat up souls, and
make yourself stronger!
And then it'll be their turn!
I gotta settle the score
with Emiya, you know?
Shinji, you fail to comprehend
the Grail's true nature.
If you truly desire the Grail,
ignore the other Masters.
They are naught
more than sacrifices.
There are other matters
that must be attended to first.
Attended to?
I am not unsympathetic
to your feelings, however.
Revenge feels divine.
To seek pleasure is
proof of being human.
Once I have done
what needs to be done,
I shall join in your games.
C-Come to think of it, I never
asked what your wish was, did I?
I approve of luxury.
Extravagant decoration
is to be admired above all.
But there is no sense in
wasting that upon the superfluous.
The superfluous?
Long ago, I selected ten slaves,
with the intent of slaying
one that would not be missed.
What do you suppose
happened, Shinji?
You killed them all, right?
I found that I could
not slay any of them.
They were simple laborers, but in
the old world, none were without value.
But this world overflows
with the superfluous.
I could choose not
only ten but thousands
and I'd not find a single one
amongst them that I could not kill.
I don't get what you're
saying. What is it that you want?
That is simple.
Too many of
anything is sickening.
We didn't understand anything
My left hand groped for
things that vanished to my touch
A moral conflict
stays your hand
and tricks you
out of your future
I don't know how
to protect anyone,
and my ideals might
well be pointless,
but I want to live my life
The past repeats before my eyes
Here I will trust the me
that now stands with you
Until my dream
crumbles and withers,
I hope you will carve
out paradise with me
Fight your fate
I've opened something
that was once closed?
If you come any closer, I hope you're
prepared to face the consequences.
Tomorrow, I'll make
you admit defeat!
I wanted to be a champion
of justice, just like Kiritsugu.
That is why your
ideals are meaningless.
A Visitor Approaches Lightly
Next Time